It all started when he met a woman.
The Tourist is a action, thriller, romance film
directed by Florian Henckel von Donnersmarck.
American tourist Frank meets mysterious British
woman Elise on the train to Venice.
Romance seems to bud, but there's more to her than meets the eye.
Frank Tupelo, played by Johnny Depp.
Elise Clifton-Ward, played by Angelina Jolie.
Inspector John Acheson, played by Paul Bettany.
Chief Inspector Jones, played by Timothy Dalton.
Reginald Shaw, played by Steven Berkoff.
The Englishman, played by Rufus Sewell.
The Tourist is a 2010 American romantic thriller film co-written and directed by Florian Henckel von
Donnersmarck and starring Angelina Jolie, Johnny Depp, Paul Bettany, and Timothy Dalton.
It is a remake of the 2005 French film Anthony Zimmer.
GK Films financed and produced the film, with Sony Pictures Worldwide
Acquisitions releasing it in most countries through Columbia Pictures.
The $100 million budget film went on to gross $278
million at the worldwide box office.
Despite negative reception from the critics, the film was nominated for three Golden Globes,
with a debate arising over the question as to whether it was a comedy or a drama.
Henckel von Donnersmarck repeatedly stated it was neither genre, calling it "a travel romance with
thriller elements," but that if he had to choose between the two, he would choose comedy.
The film explores themes of hotel, paris, france,
undercover agent, venice, italy, fake identity.
The tone is emotional and intense.